<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Questbook official blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.questbook.xyz/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Questbook official blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 14:57:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.questbook.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What Is Questbook</title>
      <link>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/what-is-questbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 14:57:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/what-is-questbook/</guid>
      <description>Questbook is in the business of increasing economic mobility of builders. We&amp;rsquo;re innovating on the future of work on multiple dimensions. Here, I&amp;rsquo;ll outline the various things that we&amp;rsquo;re launching in Q3 2022.
Permissionless work An Uber driver can get work on tap of a button, but the best of the best developers cannot get work on tap of a button. How do we fix that? In enabling this future, we first need a marketplace of capital for building and builders - for seamless matching to be possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re not a Education/Hiring Company</title>
      <link>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/clearing-confusion-about-what-questbook-is/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 14:24:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/clearing-confusion-about-what-questbook-is/</guid>
      <description>Originally seen on Twitter
This is a relevant time to clear some confusion around what we do at Questbook
People know us for our educational content.
We&amp;rsquo;re in the business of helping builders increase financial mobility.
This is the time to focus on builders and building, now that the dust around NFTs and DeFi hype has settled.
Our tutorials went viral, largely because there were no good crypto tutorials back when we launched in 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Staking Non Technical</title>
      <link>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/what-is-staking-non-technical/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 14:16:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/what-is-staking-non-technical/</guid>
      <description>Can you explain the economics behind the concept of staking from a non technical point of view? Sure. Different staking mechanisms have different mechanisms but they do have some similarities which I&amp;rsquo;ll touch upon. The basis behind the blockchain as in bitcoin was that you secure the blocks by computing a certain number every 10 mins (called nonce). That is 10 min of high intensity computation. The security assumption is that if you are spending $100 of electricity in doing the computation, and getting rewarded something that is worth $101, it&amp;rsquo;s profitable to do those computation aka mining.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Contract Wallets v/s Metamask?</title>
      <link>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/smart-contract-wallets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 13:35:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/smart-contract-wallets/</guid>
      <description>Can you explain from a user experience standpoint how a smart contract wallet is different &amp;amp; better from metamask? Smart contract wallets are not a replacement of Metamask. The fundamental to understand here is that in ethereum and crypto, code is a first class citizen. You can write code that acts and behaves on behalf of a user. In contrast, this is not the case in web2 where humans are first class citizens and code is always blocked away with tps throttling, captchas etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
