<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Questbook official blog</title><link>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Questbook official blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 19:25:41 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Launching Questbook v2 open beta</title><link>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/aug-2022-release/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 19:25:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/aug-2022-release/</guid><description>Questbook&amp;rsquo;s v2.0.1 doesn&amp;rsquo;t only provide a great user experience for foundations to run their grant program and developers to apply to them - it sets a new all time high bar for web3 dapp UX.
Context Foundations and DAOs grow the ecosystems via grants, bounties, partnerships, BD etc. These utilize funds from the community allocation, aka the treasury. With Questbook, these processes can be run on-chain - giving complete transparency and accountability to the community on where and why funds are being deployed.</description></item><item><title>Questbook Invite Links: The web3 OTP</title><link>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/questbook-invite-links/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 18:00:10 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/questbook-invite-links/</guid><description>The Problem Web3 is a nascent stack, and a major challenge dApps like QuestBook face is educating users about web3 terminology and delivering products that are easy to use products as well as decentralised.
One of QuestBook&amp;rsquo;s workflows allowed DAOs to invite their team members to their organisation on QuestBook. However, to add the user to their organisation on chain, the organisation owner had to ask their team for their respective wallet addresses &amp;ndash; which can feel unnatural, since wallet addresses have no easy-to-remember pattern like email addresses do.</description></item><item><title>Questbook proposal for Delegated Domain Allocators</title><link>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/delegated-domain-allocators/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 17:47:05 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/delegated-domain-allocators/</guid><description>Grants is an effective way to reward contributors to the ecosystem, and make the protocol more valuable. We must identify active members of our community to run our grant program rather than a centralized committee.
If you are actively contributing to the ecosystem, we believe you should also be allocated a budget to disburse as grants - to attract the highest quality builders.
Foundation money should move as close as possible to the builder, especially during the bear market.</description></item><item><title>Questbook Zapier Integration : A crashcourse in composability</title><link>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/questbook-zapier-integration/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 19:00:10 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/questbook-zapier-integration/</guid><description>Questbook is an unopinionated multisig safe for allocating funds to builders. Protocols like Polygon, Solana, Celo, Aave etc. use Questbook to run their grants/bounty programs.
Questbook is completely decentralized. We don&amp;rsquo;t own any proprietary data or run centralized servers. Even the data is either on-chain or stored on IPFS/Filecoin and delivered via Graph protocol.
Questbook itself has been built composing on various other protocols that came before us. Today, we pay it forward.</description></item><item><title>Announcing Filecoin Integration</title><link>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/announcing-filecoin-integration/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 16:47:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/announcing-filecoin-integration/</guid><description>Questbook doesn&amp;rsquo;t compromise on decentralization of the software stack. Questbook works with the best teams to push the boundaries of decentralized applications. As of today, we&amp;rsquo;re proud to announce integration with Protocol Labs &amp;amp; Filecoin.
We&amp;rsquo;ve previously talked a lot about the SACI Architecture for software applications. Storage is one of the most important parts of the tech-stack.
We don&amp;rsquo;t run our own centralized database or servers. All the data that on the grants &amp;amp; bounties tool - including creating grants, developers applying, reviewers reviewing - are all data that is stored on chain or on decentralized storage.</description></item><item><title>Your chain not supported on Questbook? No problem.</title><link>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/add-a-chain/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 19:04:19 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/add-a-chain/</guid><description>Questbook is open sourced. Questbook is a product by the community, for the community. We support multiple EVM compatible chains. You can add support for your chain on Questbook in a few simple steps.
As long as the chain meets the bare-bones requirements, it can be integrated into the product by submitting a simple PR with one YAML config file.
You can see the instructions on the questbook/chains repository. Or follow the instructions on this video :</description></item><item><title>Research at Questbook</title><link>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/research-at-questbook/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 17:42:54 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/research-at-questbook/</guid><description>Lot of infrastructure doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist for world class dapps to be built. If it doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist, we&amp;rsquo;ll build it.
There are various threads of research that we&amp;rsquo;re actively exploring at Questbook. All of these will be exposed as composable tools and public goods to build on top.
By developers. For developers.
ZK ready Gasless Smart Contract Wallets Client side burnable wallet Freshly deployed smart contract wallet for each user, with the burnable wallet as the signatory to the SCW Meta transactions relayer to pay for the gas for the first user experience EdDSA key pair to support snark proofs That way, the end user doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to have a specific wallet to interact with.</description></item><item><title>Questbook Composability</title><link>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/questbook-composability/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 17:25:19 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/questbook-composability/</guid><description>Questbook is web3 dApp. That means it is naturally composable. Since Questbook doesn&amp;rsquo;t run it&amp;rsquo;s own centralized servers and databases, all the data is always publicly visibile and can be used by builders to build great new experiences.
Here are a few ways you can compose on Questbook
Open sourced repositories You can contribute directly to our source code. 100% of our codebase is open sourced, and always will be. We don&amp;rsquo;t have any company internal private repositories or CVS.</description></item><item><title>Questbook uses a trustless software architecture</title><link>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/saci-architecture-trustless/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 16:57:54 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/saci-architecture-trustless/</guid><description>Questbook can never shutdown, even if the founders want it to. Questbook implements a completely decentralized software architecture called SACI Software Architecture
[S] Storage is decentralized This means that all the data of using the Questbook dApp is either on chain or on decentralized storage like IPFS and Filecoin.
We don&amp;rsquo;t control your data. You are in control of the data, using your keys. All the data that is private is encrypted using the public keys of the users who are allowed to access the data.</description></item><item><title>How you can use Questbook to attract Builders</title><link>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/attract-builders-using-questbook/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 16:27:35 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/attract-builders-using-questbook/</guid><description>Questbook is an Opportunity Wallet for builders. This is where builders explore opportunities to earn in crypto. These could be via Bounties, Grants or Investments you offer.
Here some of the key features of Questbook that&amp;rsquo;ll help you attract the best builders.
0. Full product Demo 1. Completely on chain : Transparent &amp;amp; Accountable program All the grants, bounties and investments programs you run will be on chain. This ensures transparency and accountability for the program.</description></item><item><title>Inviting participation to Permissionless Work Improvement Proposals</title><link>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/work-improvement-proposals/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 16:00:32 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/work-improvement-proposals/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re committed to making permissionless work a reality to help millions of builders and contributors increase their economic mobility.
The Questbook team has been working with the top DAOs and protocols to fine tune the process and deployed the first version of the workflow tool. But there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of work to be done. We need your help.
There are a few broad directions we&amp;rsquo;re actively working on
Delegated domain allocation Problems A single capital allocation (grants/bounties/investments) program has numerous blind spots and will miss lot of opportunities A single capital allocation program will result in burn-out of the folks running them Voting on all grant and bounties is an unreasonable ask from the community, and inefficient for the community Solution space Multiple domain allocators - who run capital allocation programs in their domain of expertise All the domain allocators have full ownership of how to run the program, no community voting on every decision Full transparency of performance and direction, community members can initiate a no-confidence motion upon poor performance Contribute Learn more Minimum Grants DAO with Maximum Community Participation I don&amp;rsquo;t believe in the way grants are run today Participate Permissionless Work Improvment Proposals Forum - Delegated Domain Allocation</description></item><item><title>Gasless Smart Contract Wallet Implementation</title><link>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/gasless-smart-contract-wallet-implementation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 16:33:15 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/gasless-smart-contract-wallet-implementation/</guid><description>This implementation borrows from EIP 1776 and EIP 4337. However, simplified for a the use case of letting a dapp onboard a user to their platform without having to pay for the gas or install a wallet.
Assumptions The Dapp that wants to subsidize the gas for the user is a central entity, ie. the relayer. We&amp;rsquo;re not decentralizing the relayer network as proposed in EIP 1613 User identification - OAuth A centralized relayer can subsidize the gas of the end user.</description></item><item><title>Podcasts : Tech Deepdives</title><link>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/podcasts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 14:35:43 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/podcasts/</guid><description>Tech Deepdives Bringing in technical founders and talking about the technical intricacies of their products. We&amp;rsquo;ve done multiple of these in the past. And they have been to the point, and no shilling or fuding.
&amp;ldquo;Thanks was a blast guys, good questions &amp;ndash; was this recorded btw?&amp;rdquo; - Ben Jones (CTO, Optimism)
&amp;ldquo;Thank you! You did a really great job hosting!&amp;rdquo; - Jin Chung (Cofounder, Rainbow)
Public Goods Funding Karl Floersch (Founder, Optimism) Kevin Owocki (Founder, Gitcoin) Austin Griffith (Founder, BuildGuild &amp;amp; Scaffold Eth) ZK Rollups Eli Ben-Sasson (cofounder, Starkware) Brendan Farmer (cofounder, PolygonZero) Alex Gluchowski (cofounder, Matterlabs/ZKSync) Youtube : Anchor.</description></item><item><title>Seaport and Protocol Ownership</title><link>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/seaport-protocol-ownership/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 23:30:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/seaport-protocol-ownership/</guid><description>Originally : The recent OpenSea launch of seaport is a masterstroke.
Web3 moats are in composability traction; not (just) user traction.
Firstly, the protocol launch context
https://opensea.io/blog/announcements/introducing-seaport-protocol/?amp=1
https://github.com/ProjectOpenSea/seaport
Why give away everything for free, when you could have milked profits by owning the IP?
OpenSea words the Seaport as a way to build with the community and support a generation of builders and developers. Though it may sound altruistic, it is actually in the best interest of their business to do this.</description></item><item><title>Gasless Smart Contract Wallet</title><link>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/gasless-smart-contract-wallet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 16:09:52 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/gasless-smart-contract-wallet/</guid><description>Most wallets are designed for DeFi. A wallet that works for your DApp, probably needs to be designed ground up.
Gasless I think gaslessness is an under explored opportunity in web3 - a way to interact with onchain contracts without having to pay the gas. L2s like Optimism, Arbitrum, Polygon have low gas fees - why don&amp;rsquo;t we just use a cheaper chain for on-chain transactions/interactions? If you think gaslessness is about gas prices, you&amp;rsquo;re mistaken.</description></item><item><title>Minimum Grants DAO with Maximum Community Participation</title><link>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/min-grants-dao-max-community-participation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 15:26:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/min-grants-dao-max-community-participation/</guid><description>Community participation is wrongly interpretted as vote on everything. Many grants DAO use the same model to run, what becomes, an inefficient grants program. Here, after working with a dozen grant programs in the ecosystem, I&amp;rsquo;ll lay out how you can have a grant program that is both efficient and community driven.
Delegated Capital Allocators The grant program must be divided into specialized grant programs, each with its own budget. This could be for various verticals like NFTs projects, DeFi, Infrastructure, Dev Tooling etc.</description></item><item><title>I Don't Believe in Grants (the way they're run today)</title><link>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/i-dont-believe-in-grants/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 13:21:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/i-dont-believe-in-grants/</guid><description>800 builders on Terra have lost their livelihood - in the last 1 week. Builders are losing trust on betting their careers on a chain. Terra’s collapse has downstream effects that will affect every ecosystem. Developers are leaving, leave alone attracting new developers. Now is the time to focus. If you don’t involve the community to build trust among developers - the grant program will be unfruitful.
We’ve studied various successful and unsuccessful grant programs.</description></item><item><title>What Is Questbook</title><link>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/what-is-questbook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 14:57:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/what-is-questbook/</guid><description>Questbook is in the business of increasing economic mobility of builders. We&amp;rsquo;re innovating on the future of work on multiple dimensions. Here, I&amp;rsquo;ll outline the various things that we&amp;rsquo;re launching in Q3 2022.
Permissionless work An Uber driver can get work on tap of a button, but the best of the best developers cannot get work on tap of a button. How do we fix that? In enabling this future, we first need a marketplace of capital for building and builders - for seamless matching to be possible.</description></item><item><title>We're not a Education/Hiring Company</title><link>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/clearing-confusion-about-what-questbook-is/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 14:24:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/clearing-confusion-about-what-questbook-is/</guid><description>Originally seen on Twitter
This is a relevant time to clear some confusion around what we do at Questbook
People know us for our educational content.
We&amp;rsquo;re in the business of helping builders increase financial mobility.
This is the time to focus on builders and building, now that the dust around NFTs and DeFi hype has settled.
Our tutorials went viral, largely because there were no good crypto tutorials back when we launched in 2021.</description></item><item><title>What Is Staking Non Technical</title><link>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/what-is-staking-non-technical/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 14:16:54 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/what-is-staking-non-technical/</guid><description>Can you explain the economics behind the concept of staking from a non technical point of view? Sure. Different staking mechanisms have different mechanisms but they do have some similarities which I&amp;rsquo;ll touch upon. The basis behind the blockchain as in bitcoin was that you secure the blocks by computing a certain number every 10 mins (called nonce). That is 10 min of high intensity computation. The security assumption is that if you are spending $100 of electricity in doing the computation, and getting rewarded something that is worth $101, it&amp;rsquo;s profitable to do those computation aka mining.</description></item><item><title>Smart Contract Wallets v/s Metamask?</title><link>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/smart-contract-wallets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 13:35:07 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/smart-contract-wallets/</guid><description>Can you explain from a user experience standpoint how a smart contract wallet is different &amp;amp; better from metamask? Smart contract wallets are not a replacement of Metamask. The fundamental to understand here is that in ethereum and crypto, code is a first class citizen. You can write code that acts and behaves on behalf of a user. In contrast, this is not the case in web2 where humans are first class citizens and code is always blocked away with tps throttling, captchas etc.</description></item></channel></rss>