<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Questbook official blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Questbook official blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 14:16:54 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What Is Staking Non Technical</title>
      <link>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/what-is-staking-non-technical/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 14:16:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/what-is-staking-non-technical/</guid>
      <description>Can you explain the economics behind the concept of staking from a non technical point of view? Sure. Different staking mechanisms have different mechanisms but they do have some similarities which I&amp;rsquo;ll touch upon. The basis behind the blockchain as in bitcoin was that you secure the blocks by computing a certain number every 10 mins (called nonce). That is 10 min of high intensity computation. The security assumption is that if you are spending $100 of electricity in doing the computation, and getting rewarded something that is worth $101, it&amp;rsquo;s profitable to do those computation aka mining.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Contract Wallets v/s Metamask?</title>
      <link>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/smart-contract-wallets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 13:35:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.questbook.xyz/posts/smart-contract-wallets/</guid>
      <description>Can you explain from a user experience standpoint how a smart contract wallet is different &amp;amp; better from metamask? Smart contract wallets are not a replacement of Metamask. The fundamental to understand here is that in ethereum and crypto, code is a first class citizen. You can write code that acts and behaves on behalf of a user. In contrast, this is not the case in web2 where humans are first class citizens and code is always blocked away with tps throttling, captchas etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
